## Nabeel Shaheen

Integration Consultant

3000, Melbourne, Victoria AU

Integration Consultant with 13+ years of design and development experience with emphasis on results, industry standards and best practices. Well versed in Mulesoft offerings including Anypoint Platform, API Manager, API Designer, Runtime Manager, etc. Experienced in deployment of Runtime Manager in a variety of combinations including Cloudhub, AWS Platform, Openshift/Kuberenetes and hybrid configurations.

#### SKILLS

### Solution Architecture

microservices architecture | flexible api design |

domain-driven data modelling

## Development

systems analysis | polyglot developer | application debugging | performance optimization | infrastructure support | hands-on cloud expertise

## Languages

java | groovy | python | c/c++ | javascript

### **Enterprise Integration**

mulesoft platform | apache camel | apache cxf | activemq | spring integration

### **DevOps**

docker | kuberenetes | docker-compose | monitoring and alerts

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Managing Director at Cloud Integrators Pty Ltd. March 2018- Current https://www.cloud-integrators.com.au

Integration Consultant at MLC Life Insurance June 2018- Current https://www.mlcinsurance.com.au/

Integrating financial application using Mulesoft, running on Openshift platform

Integration Consultant at City Of Melbourne February 2018- May 2018 https://www.melbourne.vic.gov.au/

- Developed and managed Cloudhub based Mulesoft platform
- Integrated with Salesforce, MDM, ActiveMQ
- Cloudhub Alerts, End-to-End, automated CI/CD using Atlassian Bamboo

### Senior Consultant at Deloitte Australia October 2016- February 2018 https://platform.deloitte.com.au/

Worked at Monash University to stengthen their integration capability by extending their Mulesoft based integration platform. Multiple projects were delivered using Mulesoft, AWS, Kuberenetes stack. Building tools and defining best-practices along the way to harness full potential of the solution

- Gather detailed business requirements and use cases, and translate technical specifications into product requirements.
- Develop flexible data models for HAL-compliant Restful APIs to facilitate evolving requirements.
- Developed GraphDB based Rest API catalog for microservices dependency analysis
- Established centralized method for maintaining data mapping across platform
- Suggest architectural improvements, design and integration solutions.
- Practices: Agile, Contract first APIs, Documentation as Code, Code Reviews.
- Technologies: Mulesoft, Kuberenetes, AWS, Java, RAML

# Senior Integration Consultant at The Marlo Group October 2015- September 2016 http://www.themarlogroup.com.au/

Worked on NBN project, building the iB2B platform using Redhat Fuse stack, to deliver complex business requirements under strict timelines. Managed onshore and offshore teams in multiple timezones.

- Technical Delivery Lead on NBN project
- Liaise with Project Managers, Designers and Test leads on Sprint tasks
- Involved in Solution design, Implementation, Code Reviews and Test Support
- Languages: Java, Groovy, Python
- Technologies: Apache Camel, ActiveMQ, Karaf, Redhat Fuse, Splunk, IBM WebSphereMQ, Citrus Framework

# Senior Integration Engineer at DGiT Consultants Ltd September 2014- September 2015 http://www.dgitsystems.com/

Developed and maintain Telflow (www.telflow.com) using Redhat Fuse stack.

- JBoss Fuse ESB container monitoring, optimization and low-level application debugging
- Component and Application Integration for Apache Camel based application
- Data transformation and mapping with external systems.
- Telflow Integration Layer: Apache Camel, ActiveMQ, Karaf
- Integration Technologies: JMS, Web services(CXF), SEDA, REST, Custom Camel Components
- Persistence: Elasticsearch, MongoDB and integration with Camel

Principal Specialist at Mobily - Etihad Etisalat Co. March 2009- September 2014

### http://mobily.com.sa/

Worked as Team lead to enhance provisioning capabilities on Telecommunication Networks.

- Participate in Telco Product Development with stake holders
- Get involved in feasibility and requirement analysis as mobile networks domain expert
- Network Integrations → vmware vCloud integration, Ericsson (MINSAT, AIR,UCIP,ACIP,HLR,HSS), Huawei(HLR, HSS), Hosted Unified Communications, mVPN)
- Mobily Service Fulfillment Transformation Project(In-house product to Comptel InstantLink)
- Subscription Renewal System for Prepaid Mobile subscribers

## Senior Software Engineer at Streaming Networks (Pvt.) Ltd. February 2007- January 2009 http://www.streaming-networks.com/

Worked as Embedded system enginer in C/C++, Assembly and Matlab to build Personal Media Recorder under resource-constrainted Environment

- Ported and developed audio codecs for devices ranging from VoIP Phones(6-8KHz) to Personal Media Recorders(44KHz)
- VLIW RISC Assembly-level development for audio codecs, FFT blocks and other signal processing filters for time/space optimization.
- Developing graphic libraries for PSP, iPhone based on SDL.
- Developed complete MPEG-4/2 AAC-LC Encoder; achieving audio quality similar to Nero's AAC Encoder and better than FAAC on most audio test samples at 128Kbps and 64Kbps.
- Optimized MPEG-4/2 AAC-LC Encoder to operate under 24 MHz (peak) with all the encoding tools enabled, on Trimedia PNX1500 processor.
- Implemented and fixed various Psychoacoustic models in Matlab and ANSI C for quality evaluation including MPEG-4 Psychoacoustic Model 2.
- mplemented & Optimized Complex & Real FFT Routines in ANSI C for reducing encoder complexity for Trimedia Platform
- Developed Audio Quality Testing Environment for audio encoders.
- Developed graphics library for PSP (Playstation Portable) platform using SDL and a playback application using PSP H.264 hardware decoder
- Languages:ANSI C/C++, SQLite, VLIW Assembly Instruction Set for Trimedia, Shell scripting, VC++
  6.0
- Debuggers:GNU prof, Visual C profile
- Platforms:Trimedia Multimedia Processors, PNX-1500/1700, Trimedia Streaming Software Architecture (TSSA), Phillips Nexperia Development Kit (NDK v5.x), PSP SDK

Research Assistant/Lecturer at COMSATS Institute of Information Technology Islamabad, Pakistan November 2004- January 2007

https://www.comsats.edu.pk/

Teaching Courses in Computer Architecture, System Programming at graduate and post graduate

level

- Conducting research in Distributed Computing/Parallel Processing
- Developing programs for High Performance Cluster Computing Lab
- Supervising Final Year Projects for Computer Engineering students
- Developed Numerical Weather Modeling Solution for Pakistan Meteorology Department using HPC Cluster.
- Developed HPC Cluster lab for the course of Distributed Computing and Parallel Programming
- Languages: C/C++, Java, Assembly
- Technologies:Parallel Processing, OSCAR Clustering Software, ROCKS Clustering Software
- APIs:MPI, PVM, LAM

#### **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor Of Science Computer Engineering** at Sir Syed University Of Engineering & Technology, Pakistan

1999 - 2003

Masters Of Science Computer Engineering at University Of Hertfordshire, Herts, UK 2003 - 2004

#### **AWARDS**

Hack the Dot at Deloitte Innovation 2017

We developed GoAgile, An intellegent assistant that participates in daily standup and updates JIRA board using speech processing, natural language processing and some glue logic

1st Prize 13th All Pakistan A. Q. Khan Software Competition at A.Q. Khan Organization 2002

We Developed an Integrated Communication Application called GRICS for this Competition held in July 2002, Islamabad.

2nd Prize in 5th All Pakistan Inter-University Software Contest at Computer Science Society Of IIUI 2002

We Developed an Integrated Communication Application called GRICS for this Competition

2nd Prize in AMICS 2002 at IQRA University 2002

We Developed a Communication Application called COM Sphere for this Competition held in January 2002, Karachi.

# 4th Prize in PROCOM 2001 at NUCES-FAST 2001

We Developed a Communication Application called COM Sphere for this Competition

1st Prize in 4th All Pakistan Inter-University Software Contest at Computer Science Society, IIUI 2001

We Developed a Server Application called WAP Sphere for this Competition